<knot name="Alpine Butterfly" style="Bend Tying">
	<description>
Uses: The Alpine Butterfly Bend is derived from the Alpine Butterfly, or Lineman's, Loop. It is one in a family of knots based on interlocking overhand knots. It is a reliable bend used to join two ropes of roughly similar size and can be untied even after being heavily loaded. The Alpine Butterfly Bend version enjoys a good reputation - probably because of its association with the better known Alpine Butterfly Loop. 
Similar Knots: The Alpine Butterfly Bend is remarkably similar to several other bends including the Zeppelin, the Hunter's, and the Ashley. Essentially these knots employ interlocking overhand knots with the ends threaded through or across the middle. David M. Delaney tested these bends and the Carrick Bend for their tendency to jam. He heavily loaded the knots tied in 1/16 inch braided nylon. The Ashley and the Hunter consistently jammed tight and would have had to be cut to release them. The Alpine Butterfly Bend, the Zeppelin, and the Carrick could all be untied easily using fingers and fingernails. Amongst the family of bends based on linked overhand knots, it would seem prudent to avoid the Ashley and the Hunter's. 
Breaking Strain: The Alpine Butterly Bend, like the other similar knots, passes the strain around the pair of ends in the middle. This double thickness should minimize the kinking and help to preserve strength. Indeed, the knot is commonly described as "one of the strongest". However, some quoted breaking strains are as low as 53% to 58% – similar to breaking strains for many other knots. 
	</description>
	<domains>
		<domain value="mountaineering"/>
		<domain value="sailing"/>
	</domains>
	<step>Join the two ends temporarily.</step>
	<step>Wind the rope around your hand.</step>
	<step>so that the join</step>
	<step>is by your finger tips.</step>
	<step>Go around</step>
	<step> again. </step>
	<step>Fold the join back </step>
	<step>and then up under</step>
	<step>the other ropes. </step>
	<step>Push the knot off your hand </step>
	<step>and tighten to see the appearance of the Alpine Butterfly. Finally, release the temporary join.</step>
</knot>
